BRYAN BILLHIMER: Hi.
Okay.
So the first thing we're going to do is talk about some of the things you're going to need.
Obviously, you're going to need a guitar.
And this little lesson isn't specific really to electric or acoustic guitar, so either is fine.
Some things will, as far as the equipment we're using might apply to electric guitar, but the lesson itself it can be done on electric or acoustic.
So we need a guitar.
I'm using a couple of cables, one to go from my guitar to my tuner and one to go from my tuner to my amp, so we need two cables if you're using a tuner, one if you're not, and electric tuner and an amplifier.
And I like to use picks so we're gonna--the lesson today involves guitar picks and there's all kinds of different guitar picks.
I have a few different ones here.
They're--they differ in thickness and size.
That's a medium pick.
I like to actually these smaller ones that are even thicker 'cause I don't like--sometimes, when you pick a string, they'll bend, these don't.
These might bend, have a little more give in 'em, but whatever--basically, whatever you feel most comfortable with.
And we're also going to need a couple of sheets of notebook paper and a pen, and if you have a music stand handy, that would be good, too.
So now we're going to go into a little bit of knowledge about the parts and terminology of the guitar.